Something big was leftover.
Cloudy with a Chance of Meatballs 2 is a animation,
family, comedy film directed by Kris Pearn.
After the disastrous food storm in the first film, Flint and
his friends are forced to leave the town.
Flint accepts the invitation from his idol Chester V to join The Live Corp Company, which has been tasked to clean the
island, and where the best inventors in the world create technologies for the betterment of mankind.
When Flint discovers that his machine still operates and now creates mutant food beasts like living pickles,
hungry tacodiles, shrimpanzees and apple pie-thons, he and his friends must return to save the world.
Flint Lockwood (voice), played by Bill Hader.
Sam Sparks (voice), played by Anna Faris.
Tim Lockwood (voice), played by James Caan.
Chester V (voice), played by Will Forte.
Brent McHale (voice), played by Andy Samberg.
Manny (voice), played by Benjamin Bratt.
Cloudy with a Chance of Meatballs is a 2009 American animated science fiction comedy film written and directed by
Phil Lord and Christopher Miller, loosely based on the 1978 children's book by Judi and Ron Barrett.
It was produced by Columbia Pictures and Sony Pictures Animation, and stars the voices
of Bill Hader, Anna Faris, James Caan, Andy Samberg, Bruce Campbell, Mr.
T, Benjamin Bratt, and Neil Patrick Harris.
The film centers around an aspiring inventor named Flint Lockwood who develops, following a
series of failed experiments, a machine that can convert water into food.
After the machine becomes rogue and begins to develop food
storms, Flint must stop it in order to save the world.
Cloudy with a Chance of Meatballs premiered at the Mann Village Theater in Los Angeles on September 12,
2009, and was released in the United States on September 18 by Sony Pictures Releasing.
It was a box office success, grossing $243 million against a budget of $100M.
The film received positive reviews from critics and was nominated for
Best Animated Feature at the 67th Golden Globe Awards.
A sequel, Cloudy with a Chance of Meatballs 2, was released in 2013,
while an animated television series premiered in 2017.
The film explores themes of inventor, villain, sequel, food, scientist.
The tone is lighthearted.